<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Helm on </title>
    <link>https://daemonza.github.io/tags/helm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Helm on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <managingEditor>werner.gillmer@gmail.com (Werner Gillmer)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>werner.gillmer@gmail.com (Werner Gillmer)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2017 Werner Gillmer</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 15:21:26 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://daemonza.github.io/tags/helm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Helm to deploy to Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://daemonza.github.io/2017/02/20/using-helm-to-deploy-to-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 15:21:26 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>werner.gillmer@gmail.com (Werner Gillmer)</author>
      <guid>https://daemonza.github.io/2017/02/20/using-helm-to-deploy-to-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;introduction:45cb11bfa871ca77409aa8598e952413&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post I will be showing how to use Helm (&lt;a href=&#34;https://helm.sh&#34;&gt;https://helm.sh&lt;/a&gt;) to build and deploy your own charts to a Kubernetes
cluster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;preface:45cb11bfa871ca77409aa8598e952413&#34;&gt;Preface&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is Helm? Well, think of it as the apt-get / yum of Kubernetes, it&amp;rsquo;s a package manager for Kubernetes
developed by the guys from Deis (&lt;a href=&#34;https://deis.com/&#34;&gt;https://deis.com/&lt;/a&gt;). If you deploy applications to Kubernetes, Helm makes
it incredibly easy to version those deployments, package it, make a release of it, and deploy, delete, upgrade
and even rollback those deployments as charts. Charts being the terminology that &lt;code&gt;helm&lt;/code&gt; use for package of
configured Kubernetes resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a second part to Helm and that is &lt;code&gt;Tiller&lt;/code&gt;. Tiller is the Helm server side that runs in Kubernetes
and handles the Helm packages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So before we can use &lt;code&gt;helm&lt;/code&gt; with a kubernetes cluster, you need to install &lt;code&gt;tiller&lt;/code&gt; on it. It&amp;rsquo;s as easy
as running :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;helm init
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;building-a-helm-chart:45cb11bfa871ca77409aa8598e952413&#34;&gt;Building a Helm chart&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s see Helm in action, using a small little Go test api I created specifically for testing use cases like this, let&amp;rsquo;s
build a helm chart of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/daemonza/testapi.git; cd testapi
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First create a skeleton structure chart&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;helm create testapi-chart
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will create a &lt;code&gt;testapi-chart&lt;/code&gt; directory. Inside this directory the three files we are the most interested in for is
Chart.yaml, values.yaml and NOTES.txt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chart.yaml describes the chart, as in it&amp;rsquo;s name, description and version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;values.yaml is stores variables for the template files templates directory. If you have more complex deployment needs, that
falls outside the default templates capability, edit the files in this directory. They are normal Go templates, Hugo (&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;https://gohugo.io&lt;/a&gt;)
which btw powers this blog, have a nice Go template primer (&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/templates/go-templates/&#34;&gt;https://gohugo.io/templates/go-templates/&lt;/a&gt;), if you need more information
on how to work with Go templates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NOTES.txt is used to give information after deployment to the user that deployed the chart. For example it might explain how
to use the chart, or list default settings, etc. For this post I will keep the default message in it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open Chart.yaml and fill out the details of the application your deploying. Using the &lt;code&gt;testapi&lt;/code&gt; as a example, this is
how my Chart.yaml looks like :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;apiVersion: v1
description: A simple api for testing and debugging
name: testapi-chart
version: 0.0.1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now open &lt;code&gt;values.yaml&lt;/code&gt; and edit it as needed. Again, using the &lt;code&gt;testapi&lt;/code&gt; as a example this is how my &lt;code&gt;values.yaml&lt;/code&gt; file
looks like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;replicaCount: 2
image:
  repository: daemonza/testapi
  tag: latest
  pullPolicy: IfNotPresent
service:
  name: testapi
  type: ClusterIP
  externalPort: 80
  internalPort: 80
resources:
  limits:
    cpu: 100m
    memory: 128Mi
  requests:
    cpu: 100m
    memory: 128Mi
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; helm lint
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;in your testapi_chart directory to make sure everything is ok.
If everything is good, you can package the chart as a release by running :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;helm package testapi-chart --debug
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to add the &lt;code&gt;--debug&lt;/code&gt; flag to see the output of the packaged chart.
Output should look similar to the following&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Saved /Users/daemonza/testapi/testapi-chart/testapi-chart-0.0.1.tgz to current directory
Saved /Users/daemonza/testapi/testapi-chart/testapi-chart-0.0.1.tgz to /Users/daemonza/.helm/repository/local
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From that we can see that the chart is placed in our current directory as well as in our local
helm repository.
To deploy this release, we can point helm directly to the chart file as follows :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;helm install testapi-chart-0.1.0.tgz
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And your output should look similar to the following :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;NAME:   ordered-quoll
LAST DEPLOYED: Wed Mar  1 09:39:48 2017
NAMESPACE: default
STATUS: DEPLOYED

RESOURCES:
==&amp;gt; v1/Service
NAME                       CLUSTER-IP   EXTERNAL-IP   PORT(S)   AGE
ordered-quoll-testapi-ch   10.0.0.133   &amp;lt;none&amp;gt;        80/TCP    0s

==&amp;gt; extensions/Deployment
NAME                       DESIRED   CURRENT   UP-TO-DATE   AVAILABLE   AGE
ordered-quoll-testapi-ch   2         2         2            0           0s


NOTES:
1. Get the application URL by running these commands:
  export POD_NAME=$(kubectl get pods --namespace default -l &amp;quot;app=ordered-quoll-testapi-ch&amp;quot; -o jsonpath=&amp;quot;{.items[0].metadata.name}&amp;quot;)
  echo &amp;quot;Visit http://127.0.0.1:8080 to use your application&amp;quot;
  kubectl port-forward $POD_NAME 8080:80
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the above we can see that a &lt;code&gt;deployment&lt;/code&gt; was created in kubernetes, the testapi got scaled to two pods and a &lt;code&gt;service&lt;/code&gt;
got created to expose the &lt;code&gt;deployment&lt;/code&gt; on the cluster IP on port 80. And the NOTES.txt file tells us how to access the
pod.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;List the deployed packages with their release versions by running :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;helm ls
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which should return output similar to the following&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;NAME        	REVISION	UPDATED                 	STATUS  	CHART
ordered-quoll	1       	Wed Mar  1 11:48:52 2017	DEPLOYED	testapi-chart-0.1.0
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modify the &lt;code&gt;Chart.yaml&lt;/code&gt; file and change the version from 0.1.0 to 0.1.1 package and deploy the 0.1.1 chart.
Running &lt;code&gt;helm ls&lt;/code&gt; again now shows us that we have two packages of the testapi deployed&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ordered-quoll	1       	Wed Mar  1 11:48:52 2017	DEPLOYED	testapi-chart-0.1.0
wishful-ibis	1       	Wed Mar  1 12:03:31 2017	DEPLOYED	testapi-chart-0.1.1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s confirm that the testapi indeed deployed, and that there is two versions of it running :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;kubectl get deployments
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should have output similar to :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;NAME                       DESIRED   CURRENT   UP-TO-DATE   AVAILABLE   AGE
ordered-quoll-testapi-cha   1         1         1            1          11m
wishful-ibis-testapi-cha    1         1         1            1           3m
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time to get rid of the older 0.1.0 deployment of the testapi chart.
Using it&amp;rsquo;s package name from &lt;code&gt;helm ls&lt;/code&gt; run :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;helm delete ordered-quoll
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Confirm again with &lt;code&gt;kubectl get deployments&lt;/code&gt; that it really is removed.
Expected output similar to :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;NAME                       DESIRED   CURRENT   UP-TO-DATE   AVAILABLE   AGE
wishful-ibis-testapi-cha   1         1         1            1           7m
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we can see the &lt;code&gt;ordered-quoll&lt;/code&gt; 0.1.0 version is removed. But what happens if we want to
go back. Imagine this scenario, we deployed a new version of a application, and for some reason its
got a problem and we need to rollback to the previous version. No worries, &lt;code&gt;helm&lt;/code&gt; got our back.
Simply run&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;helm rollback ordered-quoll 1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which means we want to rollback the testapi package ordered-quoll one revision back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expected output&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Rollback was a success! Happy Helming!
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what, if you cannot remember what the name was of a deleted package? Or just want to see all the packages that&amp;rsquo;s been
deleted? No problem, run :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;helm ls --deleted
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you want to see it ordered by date just add a &lt;code&gt;-d&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have really gone a round about way of deploying packages so far with helm, normally you would only want to
upgrade a package, instead of deploying a new version alongside it, unless off course your following a blue / green
style deployment process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s test upgrading a release. Open the testapi project, edit the Chart.yaml as a example and change the description,
and version number, package the release with &lt;code&gt;helm package .&lt;/code&gt;, but now instead of using &lt;code&gt;helm install&lt;/code&gt; run&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;helm upgrade ordered-quoll .
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will upgrade our &lt;code&gt;ordered-quoll&lt;/code&gt; release to the changes we just made. Running &lt;code&gt;helm ls&lt;/code&gt; now, you
should see the new version next to &lt;code&gt;ordered-quoll&lt;/code&gt;. And off course we can rollback this release as before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information on using  &lt;code&gt;Helm&lt;/code&gt; look at
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kubernetes/helm/blob/master/docs/using_helm.md&#34;&gt;https://github.com/kubernetes/helm/blob/master/docs/using_helm.md&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this works well, it would be nicer to put our &lt;code&gt;chart&lt;/code&gt; in a Helm repository, as it&amp;rsquo;s then easy to share
the chart or access it from other clusters, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;setting-up-helm-repository:45cb11bfa871ca77409aa8598e952413&#34;&gt;Setting up Helm repository&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Helm repository is nothing more than just a web server that&amp;rsquo;s able to serve a index.yaml file
and chart files, which is really just tar.gz file containing the generated kubernetes resource manifest files from our helm chart
templates. So almost any web server will do. For local testing
you can also use the helm command itself. Here is a example of helm serving the charts from a &lt;code&gt;charts&lt;/code&gt;
directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;helm serve --repo-path ./charts
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Problem is you need to get your charts onto the web server somehow, and there is a myriad amount of solutions
on how to do it, it can as a example be as simple as just using &lt;code&gt;scp&lt;/code&gt; to get your chart to the web server, or setting up
Caddy(&lt;a href=&#34;https://caddyserver.com/&#34;&gt;https://caddyserver.com/&lt;/a&gt;) with the Upload plugin(&lt;a href=&#34;https://caddyserver.com/docs/upload&#34;&gt;https://caddyserver.com/docs/upload&lt;/a&gt;). You can also use AWS S3 or
a Google GCS bucket as well to host a chart repository, which does make uploading easier, by using the google cloud command
line utility or the UI or for S3 use one of the many S3 tools out there. I personally prefer s3cmd (&lt;a href=&#34;http://s3tools.org/s3cmd&#34;&gt;http://s3tools.org/s3cmd&lt;/a&gt;)
for uploading files to S3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However I wanted something a little simpler, that generates the Helm index for me, without me having to do it by hand, and also
be able to host it myself in a Kubernetes cluster, so I wrote a  small &lt;code&gt;Go&lt;/code&gt; server called &lt;code&gt;Helmet&lt;/code&gt; to act as my helm
repository. It&amp;rsquo;s basically just a web server, to which you can upload chart files using something like &lt;code&gt;curl&lt;/code&gt; and it then
handles the repository indexing for you using helm in the backend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find out more about &lt;code&gt;Helmet&lt;/code&gt; at
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/daemonza/helmet&#34;&gt;https://github.com/daemonza/helmet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;using-a-helm-repository:45cb11bfa871ca77409aa8598e952413&#34;&gt;Using a Helm repository&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using &lt;code&gt;Helmet&lt;/code&gt; as our helm repository, let&amp;rsquo;s deploy it to our Kubernetes cluster and then add a chart.
And off course we can deploy &lt;code&gt;Helmet&lt;/code&gt; with Helm :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/daemonza/helmet.git; cd helmet/helmet-chart
helm package . --debug
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A helmet chart should be created, in my case it is &lt;code&gt;helmet-chart-0.0.1.tgz&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deploy the same way we deployed the testapi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;helm install helmet-chart-0.0.1.tgz --debug
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this blog post, I deployed everything to Kubernetes Minikube(&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kubernetes/minikube&#34;&gt;https://github.com/kubernetes/minikube&lt;/a&gt;)
So using minikube, let&amp;rsquo;s see how we can access &lt;code&gt;helmet&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;HELMET=(`kubectl get services | awk &#39;/helmet/ {print $1}&#39;`)
minikube service $HELMET --url
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which gives me back &lt;code&gt;http://192.168.99.100:31162&lt;/code&gt;. Using this URL, let&amp;rsquo;s add it as a helm repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;helm repo add helmet http://192.168.99.100:31162/charts/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And confirm that our &lt;code&gt;helmet&lt;/code&gt; repo is there by running &lt;code&gt;helm repo list&lt;/code&gt;.
You should see the following :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;NAME  	URL
stable	https://kubernetes-charts.storage.googleapis.com/
helmet	http://192.168.99.100:31162/charts/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can now add our testapi chart to this &lt;code&gt;helmet&lt;/code&gt; repository with :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl -v -T testapi-chart-0.1.1.tgz -X PUT http://192.168.99.100:31162/upload/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can confirm that the chart is uploaded and the helm repo index got created by running&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl http://192.168.99.100:31162/charts/index.yaml
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which will give us the following output :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;apiVersion: v1
entries:
  testapi-chart:
  - apiVersion: v1
    created: 2017-03-01T12:11:09.746867088Z
    description: A Helm chart for Kubernetes
    digest: fe0c17d87b523c91cc59bd1e4d2f997defb2a215c4cc0fc02a1725922471e88a
    name: testapi-chart
    urls:
    - http://masked-macaw-helmet-char:1323/charts/testapi-chart-0.1.1.tgz
    version: 0.1.1
generated: 2017-03-01T12:11:09.746407601Z
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can now search for the testapi, across all our repositories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;helm search testapi
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expected output :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;NAME                	VERSION	DESCRIPTION
helmet/testapi-chart	0.1.1  	A Helm chart for Kubernetes
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s try searching for something else. Searching for Jenkins gives us this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;NAME          	VERSION	DESCRIPTION
stable/jenkins	0.1.14 	Open source continuous integration server. It s...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which we can see comes from the &lt;code&gt;stable&lt;/code&gt; repository. Very nice! Have I mentioned I love helm? :D
Now, to continue  let&amp;rsquo;s install the testapi from our &lt;code&gt;helmet&lt;/code&gt; repository :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;helm install helmet/testapi-chart
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s how simple it is to use helm repositories. We can now use this &lt;code&gt;helmet&lt;/code&gt; helm repository from anywhere
upload charts to and deploy from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;ci-cd:45cb11bfa871ca77409aa8598e952413&#34;&gt;CI / CD&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Helm makes continuous integration and deployment a lot easier with Kubernetes. For example one strategy of doing it could
be, matching up your git branches to helm repositories.
Imagine you are busy building a application, and you have two branches (develop, master), master is your stable
branch and anything there could be deployed to a production kubernetes cluster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example of your develop and stable helm repositories :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;helm develop add helmet http://repositoryone:31162/charts/
helm master add helmet http://repositorythree:31162/charts/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Write your code on a develop branch, and on a git push, Jenkins picks up that there was a change, build your code, run your
tests, and create a helm chart and uploads that chart to your &lt;code&gt;develop&lt;/code&gt; helm repository. From there you can then
easily deploy it into your development Kubernetes cluster (minikube for example). A push to master might trigger
Jenkins to deploy the code as a stable release to your master repository and then deploy it to your production kubernetes
cluster. Using a simple setup like this it becomes easy to deploy either develop level quality packages or stable
packages to kubernetes clusters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Jenkins(&lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins.io/&#34;&gt;https://jenkins.io/&lt;/a&gt;) you can use the this plugin(&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jenkinsci/kubernetes-ci-plugin&#34;&gt;https://github.com/jenkinsci/kubernetes-ci-plugin&lt;/a&gt;) for
easy helm usage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;conclusion:45cb11bfa871ca77409aa8598e952413&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Helm makes doing reliable reproducible deployments ridiculously easy to Kubernetes, and I cannot recommend enough
to make it part of your standard way of working with Kubernetes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>